Stop.
Unclip.
Go on.
Stop! If I told you to jump.
what would you do? Jump?
We're looking for people
who can think. not sheep.
It's over for you.
Okay. you can send the next one.
Villiers!
Next up. Villiers.
Alright. you can go.
Go on.
Stop. Look at me.
Raise your arms.
Unclip yourself.
No.
"No"? Are you afraid of taking risks?
I don't take unnecessary risks.
Alright. you can go to the end.
Stop! Raise your knee.
Now sing.
Sing!
The blue sky above us could collapse
I can't hear anything! Can you?
And the Earth might as well crumble
I don't care. as long as you love me
I couldn't care less
About the rest of the world
As long as love fills my mornings
Stop.
What's with the sappy song?
I'm a hopeless romantic. Major.
Alright. you can come back.
Wait.
Why are you here?
To join the GIGN Tactical Force.
Why?
It's the most effective tactical force--
Stop with your recruitment bullshit.
Why are you here. Max?
Because I can be the best.
Better than your father?
What makes you think
that you have what it takes?
The truth is. I don't know.
It's the only thing I want.
I'll do anything to prove myself.
Next. Lemoine.
What do they ask you on the beam?
Just some bullshit to throw you off.
You were right to push him.
You don't want people to think
you're favoring your godson.
You did the right thing.
ELITE FORCE
NATIONAL GENDARMERIE
GIGN
Come on. guys. That's weak.
Come on.
Shooters. when you're ready.
start the count.
Shooter one. ready.
Shooter two. ready.
HOSTAGES FREED IN DARING GIGN OPERATION
Three. two. one.
KOUACHI
THE FINAL ASSAULT
Thirteen.
Fourteen.
Fifteen.
CAUTION
ELECTRIC FENCE
Hey.
France Info.
General Paloméros will be our guest with--
Where are you?
I'm coming! I'm here.
That looks cute.
Is it new?
-This?
-Yeah.
Yeah. do you like it?
Yeah. it's nice.
Do you have the matching bottoms?
Take a guess.
Show me.
No. I don't think I will.
-Come on. show me.
-No.
I'll show you when you resign
and move back to Paris.
I'm waiting until recruitment's over.
Hi. sweetheart.
Go ahead. help yourself.
Like you'd say no.
Hi. sweetheart.
Forget it. she's gone.
She doesn't care. she's 16.
Not even a hi for her dad.
I'll see her tonight.
I'll come straight to the conservatory.
That was yesterday.
-You're messing with me.
-I'm not.
Her rehearsal has always been on the 5th.
Fuck.
I was sure it was tonight.
How was it?
ALERT 1
I love you. I have to go. I'll call you.
Go.
This is the army's weapons depot
in Châteaudun.
Four soldiers shot dead.
I can see that.
Two other soldiers are missing.
They may have been taken hostage.
It happened fast. Very violent.
-Kalash. Kalash. and an Uzi?
-Yeah. an Uzi.
It's clear the terrorists
know the site very well.
They destroyed several of the cameras.
They move precisely. They stay calm.
These guys are pros.
We're looking for clues to identify them.
They're used to working together.
They could be mercenaries.
But why take such a big risk for weapons?
You can get them anywhere.
This is a bit unusual.
Those pallets contain explosives.
CL20. a compound
still under military testing.
-That's what they stole.
-It'd just been delivered.
It's the most powerful explosive known.
One ton of it.
-Do we know where they are?
-Not yet.
Intel are on it. We just got the footage.
They'll find them.
I reassigned Tanya to your section.
Stop the truck and retrieve the cargo.
You're in command.
You're not coming?
The men don't need me. I'm staying at HQ.
Wait. there's a camera
they didn't take out.
Let's see.
Look. there. On the roof.
-A cooling unit.
-Yeah.
That means it has a GPS chip.
We'll check with the investigators
and track it down.
Your section is on the ground.
-You're the helicopter gunner.
-Okay.
A Caracal just arrived from Villacoublay.
-We'll stick with 82.
-Very well.
Chloé. keep us posted
on that refrigerator truck.
Will do.
COMMIT FOR LIFE
NATIONAL GENDARMERIE
-Start the battery.
-Battery.
I'll handle the radios.
-Stick recentered. Checklist completed.
-Roger.
Okay. go.
Take vehicle four.
Hey. Tanya.
Glad to have you with us. Miss Explosive.
-You good?
-Yeah. you?
-Priority to Tactical.
-Mustache. respect your elders.
Get in the other car.
Don't forget. I can blow your balls off.
Valère's tiny little balls!
Come with me.
Nice car.
Yeah. it was seized in a drug run
at the Spanish border last week.
They're leaving!
Shouldn't we finish up?
Mop the floor if you want.
we're going to watch.
AIR AND SPACE FORCE
Let's go.
We'll expand.
-Sit down.
-General.
Vertical climb. increasing power.
We've got him.
The GPS shows him on a back road
heading towards Chartres. 40 km away.
Everyone head for the A10.
There may be two hostages.
What are you doing?
Villiers. Colonel.
We heard about the op.
We came to show our support.
Stand in the corner. Not a peep.
Invisible. Understood?
Visual on target.
Kilometer 81. he's heading south.
Target alone. No other vehicles.
He's driving fast.
There's a town 1.5 km ahead.
There's also a school
at the town entrance.
That could be a target.
It's transporting one ton of CL20.
It could wipe out the entire area.
I'll stop them before that.
If it flips over.
it could explode and take you with it.
If you have a better idea. I'm all ears.
Otherwise. you know what you have to do.
Everyone. move back.
Cédric. stay back and move in afterward.
Alright. we'll keep our distance.
Move across to the left!
The school is 1 km ahead.
There's a school bus approaching.
They'll cross paths in 800 meters.
The driver is alone in the cab.
Target immobilized.
Right next to the bus.
There are a lot of kids.
Shit!
I'm going down.
No. I'm the negotiator.
Negative. take care of the bus.
The bus is blocked.
There's nothing I can do. I'm stuck!
Look. they're lowering a rope.
Gendarmerie. put your hands up!
Put your hands up!
There he is. He's coming.
I want to see your hands above your head!
Raise both hands
above your head right now!
Put your hands up!
I'm not armed. They forced me.
I had no choice.
They forced me. I swear.
I have to blow myself up.
It's too late now.
Raise your hands above your head.
fingers interlocked.
Team Alpha in position.
Open up!
Hello. children. Everything is fine.
We're going to get off the bus together.
My wife and kids are at home.
They'll kill them
if I don't deliver this shipment.
Raise your hands up. now.
Bus evacuation underway.
Second team approaching.
Both hands. Your other hand.
My name is Sergeant Osman.
I'll check.
Move forward. Try to stay calm.
Ma'am. take a few of the kids
and we'll get off the bus calmly.
It's my family or me. I have no choice.
Raise your left hand.
I need to see what's in your left hand!
Fuck.
He has a release trigger.
-Please.
-Come on. that's good.
Cédric. move it.
It could go off any minute.
-Come on. guys.
-Let's go.
Tanya. any updates?
There are crates. I'll inspect the door.
Osman is one of the soldiers
who disappeared from the base.
-Okay.
-He may be a hostage.
Okay. Sergeant Osman. is that it?
-Yes.
-We're sending a team to find his family.
Everything's fine.
Go help the others with the kids.
Sergeant Osman. look.
I'm putting my weapon away.
Okay.
-I'm scared.
-Keep moving.
Keep running. don't stop.
Will they shoot?
Don't stop.
Door check okay. opening now.
I'm getting in.
Look at me.
Everything's fine.
Look at me. Stay with me. please.
I'm going to slowly approach your door
and open it so we can talk. Is that okay?
I'm opening the door.
Look at me.
Look at me. Do you have kids?
Sarah and Nora.
Sarah and Nora are lovely names.
They're at home.
I know. What we're doing here with you.
we're also doing for your family at home.
Bus evacuated. The children are safe.
No parallel circuit.
Everything's connected to the trigger.
Look at me.
I want you to think about your daughters.
The more you think about them.
the harder you squeeze. okay?
Alright.
Squeeze your left hand.
-Squeeze it. very hard.
-Okay.
David. I need his trigger
in order to disarm the system.
About 60 CL20 tubes are connected.
You can lower your right hand.
That's it. Great. look at me.
Now. reach out your left hand.
Very slowly.
Reach out your left hand.
Look at me. Osman.
I can't do anything. I need the detonator.
Think about your daughters.
That's great. Keep going.
You're doing great.
Look at me. Osman.
Fantastic. That's it.
Everything's fine.
We can free you from this now.
It's almost over.
Well done. Sergeant.
NATIONAL GENDARMERIE
GIGN
We found Osman's family
unharmed at their home.
Tied up and gagged.
The hostage takers had left a while ago.
The sergeant didn't know.
so he kept following orders.
His mission was to drop off the cargo
in an abandoned parking lot near Chartres.
He was ordered to blow himself up
if we intercepted him.
We stopped him.
At the meeting point.
we found a second refrigerator truck
that we hadn't seen on the cameras.
Inside. a driver.
The second soldier taken hostage.
Shot dead.
He was given the same orders as Osman.
They threatened to kill his family too.
They killed him
when he delivered the cargo.
We didn't find anything
in the back of the truck.
But he was definitely
transporting stolen CL20.
Their operation was sophisticated.
professional even.
It was deliberate
and had been planned long ago.
Tanya. go ahead.
CL20 is a cutting-edge explosive.
Originally. it was a failed pesticide
made in the USA.
-Can you start the video. please?
-Yeah.
This is the DGA's testing base.
A test from five years ago.
That was just 2 kilos.
It's the most powerful
conventional explosive.
Extremely difficult to handle.
Less than ten people
in Europe are trained in it.
The last time I saw it was in Afghanistan.
An American stock.
France has never publicly admitted
to synthesizing it.
Yet that's what was stolen last night.
One ton. And only half of it
was in the van we intercepted.
-So 500 kilos are still out there.
-Yes.
Versailles SR
and the DGSI are on the case.
Intelligence and Reconnaissance
are at their disposal.
Christophe. will you brief the FI?
Yes. General. I'll take care of it.
Okay. guys. Let's go.
-Eat?
-Yeah.
Let's go.
It takes balls
to hit a weapons depot like that.
They're audacious.
We'll never hear the end of it.
I won't be here anymore.
Hello. Houston. anybody there?
When did we last talk?
-We're talking now.
-No. really talk.
Yesterday you showed me
that awful motorbike you want to--
David.
What's wrong?
Pancreatic cancer. Stage three.
That's what's wrong.
The doctor says I have 5 to 6 months left.
Maybe seven. I'm a stubborn bastard.
But it's over.
It's over?
What do you mean? "It's over"?
You talk like that?
You got this far talking like that?
There are some battles
you can't prepare for.
We're not trained for this.
I won't win this fight. It's over.
So. I'm quitting.
I want time with my family.
You've neglected yours too.
Yeah.
David.
Don't feel guilty about leaving.
It's the right decision for you and Jess.
-Yeah.
-She's been waiting for too long.
You had the best missions.
I'll spare you Max's file.
You can't stay if he graduates.
You know very well he won't graduate.
Always a joy dining with you.
Is there anyone in this place?
Where's Manon?
She went to the gym.
-That's good.
-Yeah.
Thanks.
I can't believe it about Christophe.
It's tough.
Has it made you
reconsider your resignation?
No. quite the opposite.
I've made up my mind.
We have to make our dream come true.
A sailing trip around the world.
I'll announce it
at the graduation ceremony.
I want to do things right.
And Max? He's about to graduate.
-You're going to leave him all alone?
-No. but…
There's no way Max will graduate.
Max won't graduate.
So?
Ready for the trip of a lifetime?
Shit. Mom. actually.
my class is at 9:00 a.m.
-Dad?
-Hey.
I didn't know you were here.
-What?
-You guys are acting weird.
-No. you're acting weird.
-Yeah. super weird.
-Yeah.
-Yeah. that must be it. Okay.
Mom. can you drive me. please?
No. I'm going to work.
It'll take four hours on the subway.
Go get your helmet. I'll take you.
Are you sure?
What? Can't I take my daughter
to her piano lesson?
-Go get your helmet.
-I'll get changed.
-Okay.
-Wow. this is a first.
I love you.
It's 8:42 a.m.
The 17th district is 6 minutes away.
-Plenty of time.
-What? The 17th?
You know. I'll be able to take you
to the conservatory more often.
And spend more time with you
if you're not too embarrassed.
-We'll spend more time together.
-But…
Great. but Dad.
it's no longer in the 17th.
My new conservatory is in Saclay.
-Saclay?
-Yes.
Okay. we'll be on time.
-Hold on tight.
-We won't be on time. Crap.
What is this. Club Med? You're not cold?
No!
That's bullshit. even I'm cold.
You're not cold?
Yeah. to be honest. we're freezing.
You only had to say.
We're not assholes here.
We'll give you some gear to warm up.
Some nice heaters.
Here. are you cold?
Come on. Raise your arms.
-It warms you up. huh?
-It sure does.
Pass it to your buddy.
And with a smile. guys.
Be careful with that one.
it's the General's. so…
Better not put it down.
Three. two. one. go.
Joining the GIGN
puts you among the top tier.
The elite of all tactical forces.
But it doesn't come easy!
If I go into battle.
I need to know that I can put my life
in my squadmates' hands.
If you want to be part of it.
we have to be absolutely certain
that we can do the same with you.
Come on. I'll add a little atmosphere.
It's a smoke bomb.
Don't stop. come on!
Come on!
I see some of you shaking.
If you're tired. you can put it down.
I'm sorry.
You can try again next year.
100 meters away.
At 100 meters.
one click equals one centimeter.
I want to see you put five bullets
right between the eyes.
Good luck. gentlemen.
Two weeks ago. there were 100 of you.
How many of you are here tonight?
Fourteen.
It's the end of recruitment.
If you don't have what it takes.
let me make it clear. we don't care.
We won't take on any of you.
None.
On the other hand.
for those of you who are still here
at the end of this process.
you'll have earned your spot.
Don't forget you're doing this
for under 2000 bucks.
If you want to give up. now's the time.
Still not eliminated?
Still haven't given up?
Come on. keep pushing. ma'am.
Congratulations. it's a boy.
If you're lucky enough to join my section.
and Cédric's.
then we will give our lives for you too.
But in the meantime. arms outstretched!
We're going to change the next test.
Defusing.
It's odd to change it at the last minute.
We don't deal with explosives.
Cédric. we dealt
with explosives yesterday.
It can happen.
We have to adapt
and be ready for anything.
-Is this because of Max?
-Yeah.
Don't be such an ass. David.
You do know what this means to him?
We're on a mission. there's a bomb.
and he freezes. What then?
Stop. This isn't to test him.
It's to make him screw up.
You're scared
he'll end up like his father.
Djibril. we're changing the last exercise.
Stop everything. guys.
We're changing exercises.
Look at me.
Come on. buddy.
Tanya to Max. do you copy?
Loud and clear.
Catch your breath. Breathe.
That's it. Now move forward.
-And observe.
-Hey.
There's a wire.
It goes toward the stairs.
It goes toward…
It goes toward an electric panel.
It's…
Shit. I triggered something.
Well done. You have one minute.
I see an improvised explosive device.
A tube. some wires.
Okay. I know which one to cut.
Disarmed.
Congratulations!
Yeah. come on. make some noise!
She said yes!
I'm getting married. guys!
Congratulations!
-Yeah.
-It's going to be a great ceremony.
-Great start.
-Yeah.
-General.
-Hello. Jess. If you'll excuse me.
How are you?
Thanks for your message.
-It's the big night. huh?
-Yeah.
Have you seen David?
No. I haven't.
It's been a while.
Fifteen years.
You promised he'd never be admitted.
Nathalie.
I did everything I could.
I even sabotaged all his tests.
I was much harder on him than anyone else.
What do you want me to do? Max is…
He's talented.
Talent doesn't stop you getting killed.
If I lose him too…
This fucking place…
It took Laurent from me.
Now it's taking my son.
Promise me
that you'll protect him.
That you'll never leave Max on his own.
Do you hear me?
Never.
Don't forget that it's because of you
that I lost my husband.
Pierre-Jean Lemoine.
Tactical Force. section one.
Wear it with dignity and pride.
Well done. PJ!
Groom to be!
NATIONAL GENDARMERIE INTERVENTION GROUP
Raphaëlle Ricci.
Intelligence and Reconnaissance Force.
Wear it with dignity and pride.
Well done. Rapha!
You're the best!
Well done!
You earned it!
Maxime Villiers.
Tactical Force. section one.
Wear it with dignity and pride.
Well done. Max!
Well done!
I believe you wanted to add something?
-Yeah. David!
-Davido!
Sorry. I'm not very good at speeches.
Today is a special day. Very special.
For you as well as for me.
Because after a brutal selection process.
you are now part of the group.
Congratulations.
It's an exceptional group
that you will be living with.
It's a bit like a family.
A demanding family.
One that will demand sacrifices.
And you'll only be able
to make those sacrifices
if you have the support of your families.
However. your families…
didn't choose this.
They're subject to it.
So. thank you.
Thank you because
you are the ones
who have to show the most courage.
You have to put up with
the constant delays.
The beepers going off.
The fear in your gut
when they go on a mission that's
difficult.
Then there's the distance.
At the end of the day.
maybe the true heroes
are your families.
Let's get the party started.
See you in the field tomorrow.
-Thank you!
-Yeah. David!
Bravo!
Thanks for everything you've done.
-Of course. You've earned your place.
-Thanks.
David. where are you going? Come back.
I can't leave Max.
I can't.
I was offered a position at the bank.
It's a huge promotion.
That's great.
But it's in Singapore.
I didn't tell you about it because
there was no point.
I knew you wouldn't give it all up
to come with me. and…
For me. the most important thing
has always been our family.
But obviously. it's different for you.
Manon and I don't come first.
You do. but…
Jess…
And Max?
Will you tell him
why you're doing all this?
Give me some time. please.
As for Singapore.
I'm going to say yes.
I'll head back to Paris now.
Why the Tactical Force?
Sure. they're the best of the best. but…
I mean. what's the real reason?
David and my father
were in the same section.
They were like brothers. and…
One day. an op went wrong.
The explosion?
Yeah.
Fifteen years ago.
after my father's death.
my mother wanted us
as far away from the GIGN as possible.
I only came back this year.
But my real home has always been here.
In Satory.
In Tactical. like my father.
And you. Intel?
Intelligence and Reconnaissance.
Was that your goal?
Why are you being condescending
all of a sudden?
Intelligence and Reconnaissance
was my dream. you know?
It's my calling.
Plus. I'm good at it.
Tracking down guys. following leads…
Honestly. I don't get you. David.
At least remove Max
from your section. damn it!
I forgave you.
But does he know what really happened?
No.
How are you gonna handle
having him with you in the field?
How?
You think you're staying for him.
You're delusional.
You're kidding yourself.
Subtitle translation by: Alison Simpson